okay so we're at the top of the hour so
好吧，我们现在处于忙碌状态
I suggest we slowly get into the coal so
我建议我们慢慢进入煤里
everyone out there thank you for joining
大家都谢谢你的加入
this is the June update call for Jakarta
这是雅加达的六月更新电话
enthusiasts we're thrilled to have you
爱好者，我们很高兴拥有您
in the coal and as always we will place
在煤炭中，我们将一如既往地
the recording and all the materials that
录音和所有材料
were using on this call at the community
正在社区中使用此电话
folder and yeah we're ready to to go
文件夹，是的，我们准备好了
ahead and start so this is our agenda
前进并开始，所以这是我们的议程
for today and we'll start with Mitri and
今天，我们将从Mitri和
AD and Eve are on Jakarta ee8 release
AD和Eve在Jakarta ee8版本上
and updates related to that so um and I
以及与此相关的更新
know you said you're ready so stop
知道你说你准备好了，所以停下来
sharing on my end and just hand it over
分享我的心，然后交出
to you okay thanks Tanya let's see if I
谢谢，Tanya，让我们看看我是否
can get this working so all right is
可以使它正常工作
that look good to everybody yeah yeah
对每个人都很好看是的
seems to be off the bottom there but
似乎不在那儿了，但是
okay so I just wanted to give a quick
好吧，我只想快速讲一下
overview about the high-level goals for
有关以下方面的高级目标的概述
this Jakarta 8 release it's not my
这个雅加达8版本不是我的
intent to undersell this I'm just trying
打算卖掉这个，我只是想
to give everybody a you know a feel for
给大家一个你知道的感觉
what what it is we're actually
我们到底是什么
delivering and what are the tasks that
交付以及哪些任务
you know the top level things that we're
你知道我们最重要的事情
working on let's see
正在努力，让我们看看
so for jacquard ee8 the high level
因此对于提花ee8来说是高级
deliverables are essentially just we
可交付成果本质上就是我们
want to release this the same set of
想要发布同一套
compliance and and quality criteria
符合性和质量标准
we're gonna release those two am a tweet
我们要发布这两个推文
when we released the the Eclipse
当我们发布Eclipse
GlassFish 5.1 so eclipse GlassFish 5.1
GlassFish 5.1使其黯然失色GlassFish 5.1
was tested Andy as sort of is listed as
经过安迪的测试，列为
a certified compatible Java EE eight
认证的兼容Java EE八
application server and we're basically
应用服务器，我们基本上
going to use that as the sort of the
将使用它作为那种
keystone for a a confirmation that all
确认一切的基石
of the TCK is all the rest of the
TCK的其余部分
material that would verify compliance is
可以证明符合性的材料
identical to what we had in Java EE 8
与我们在Java EE 8中相同
but contributed licensed and approved
但贡献了许可和批准
and ratified by then then all of the new
然后在那时批准所有新
Jaccard EE specifications the
Jaccard EE规范
specification process the ttk
规格说明
requirements etc so in some ways if you
要求等，如果您以某种方式
think about this in terms of its
考虑它的
functionality so it's really just a
功能，所以它实际上只是一个
licensing change licensing and branding
许可变更许可和品牌
and it said effectively that will
它有效地表示，
complete all of the all of the
完成所有的所有
contributions at least from well it
贡献至少来自于它
should complete all the contributions
应该完成所有的贡献
for Java EE 8 and the Ilham will be able
Java EE 8和Ilham将能够
to sort of leapfrog off that and move
跳过那一步然后移动
firmly and rapidly into a the delivery
坚决迅速地交付
of you know the next next functional
你们知道下一个下一个功能
updates for Jakarta e8 so each
Jakarta e8的更新，因此每个
specification will be ratified by the
规格将由
jacquard ee8 the char de processes the
提花ee8的char de处理
specifications themselves probably many
规范本身可能很多
of you know this there'll be a
你们当中知道会有一个
specification document an API release a
规范文档API版本a
TCK and then we will verify that
TCK，然后我们将验证
everything tests out and meets the
一切都经过测试并符合
compatibility requirements for the
的兼容性要求
Jakarta release process for those of you
雅加达针对您的发布过程
who don't know you know we will be there
谁不知道你知道我们会在那里
are sort of two guiding documents that
是两种指导性文件，
will be following there's the Eclipse
将跟随着Eclipse
Foundation specification process you
基础规范流程
might see that abbreviated EF SP from
可能会看到来自的缩写EF SP
time to time and then wayne's ax
时不时，然后韦恩的斧头
we written up a blog that says you know
我们写了一个博客说你知道
it's sort of a RiRi at rewrites that in
有点像RiRi
a you know what does this mean to me in
你知道这对我意味着什么
a step-by-step you know process so and
逐步了解流程
then the last then building on that the
然后最后的基础上
way that
这样
Cosette
珂赛特
um you cast their general and a distance
嗯，你把他们的一般和距离
and will
还会
[Music]
[音乐]
and
和
that's that
就是这样
you
您
ah
啊
[Music]
[音乐]
you
您
so have dime Oh gravity
所以有毛钱哦重力
beat the button but the ordinary kept it
击败按钮，但普通保留
out
出
you
您
me too horrible tea and Cotton's free
我太恐怖了，棉花免费
artiste first Jakarta really there will
雅加达第一艺术家真的会在那里
back to block and the work is a his name
回到街区，作品就是他的名字
you know a new potential to be with
你知道一个新的潜力
Burke we're trialing through lease
伯克，我们正在通过租赁进行试用
process there the specification is
在那里处理规范
ballot being for there I I think there's
选票在那里，我认为那里
certain reviews so the weekend the
某些评论，所以周末
create occasions are part of Java will
创建场合是Java的一部分
be will be released and ready to go look
将被释放，准备去看看
for these to be combined together in
将它们组合在一起
bulk ballots and it's the specification
大量选票及其规格
committee in the steering committees
指导委员会中的委员会
that will vote on these um a key feature
这将对这些um进行投票
of the Jakarta II released was the open
雅加达II的发行是公开的
sourcing of the jacquard ET CK's what's
提花ET CK的货源是什么
in the TCK the TCK itself collection of
在TCK中，TCK本身的集合
documentation exclude lists and you know
文档排除列表，您知道
and basically this is originally this
基本上这是原来的
was a standalone I guess required part
我想是一个独立的部分
of each API but most of us didn't get to
每个API，但我们大多数人都没有
look at those because they were licensed
看那些因为他们被许可了
by Oracle now they're available open
由Oracle提供，现已开放
source the tzk project is open source
tzk项目是开源的
and all the TCK jobs are currently well
目前所有的TCK工作都很好
most of the tzk jobs are currently
目前大多数tzk职位
combined in ace in a in Eclipse Eclipse
在Eclipse中与ace结合
operated Jenkins server so there's a lot
运营的Jenkins服务器，所以有很多
of information here a lot of stuff is
的信息很多东西是
written about how these work and I
写下有关这些工作原理的信息，我
assume that more and more people will
假设越来越多的人会
dig in and get their hands dirty with
深入挖掘并弄脏他们的手
the tcks as things move forward they're
随着事情的发展，他们正在
already being built they're already be
已经被建造，他们已经被
already running against them Eclipse
已经针对他们运行Eclipse
class 55.1 the results are essentially
55.1级，结果基本上是
there as stable as we have ever seen as
像我们见过的那样稳定
they have ever been
他们曾经
we're trying to work with the eclipse
我们正在尝试与日食
admins to even to improve that stability
管理员甚至提高了稳定性
even farther so just some quick
甚至更远，所以只是一些快速
questions that I came up with
我想到的问题
right so we are using the same T CK's -
对，所以我们使用相同的T CK-
we're using these jacquard ET CK's to
我们正在使用这些提花ET CK
validate that all of the released API
验证所有已发布的API
jars are are proven with that were
罐子被证明与
proven to be a compatible couple of
被证明是兼容的
questions that have come up can
提出的问题可以
components generate an update release in
组件在中生成更新版本
this in this engine are d8 as long as
这个在这个引擎上只要是d8
they still passed the jacquard e8t CK's
他们仍然通过了提花e8t CK
and or cts that's fine people have asked
和/或cts很好，人们问过
if there's going to be a new GlassFish
如果会有新的GlassFish
release I don't think currently the
发布我不认为目前
GlassFish team has some has put up to
GlassFish团队已经提出了一些建议
put together a plan for that if it
为此制定一个计划
decides to do that we could release any
决定这样做，我们可以释放任何
new GlassFish but that's not a must-have
新的GlassFish，但这不是必须的
for this particular project so
对于这个特定的项目
essentially if project teams want to
本质上是项目团队想要
make releases we could try to
发布我们可以尝试的版本
accommodate that
容纳那个
in the release schedule but our goal is
在发布时间表中，但我们的目标是
verify the tcks work and verifies the
验证tcks的工作并验证
tcks past what they you know in the same
在同一时间越过你知道的事情
way that they have before well sometimes
有时候他们以前的方式
people will ask how can I help there's a
人们会问我该如何帮助
lot of ways we can we could use you know
我们可以使用很多方法来使用您知道的
we could use community help there's a
我们可以利用社区的帮助
lot of text that needs to be updated for
需要更新的大量文本
things like switching over from how to
从如何切换到
you know how did Oracle provide support
您知道Oracle如何提供支持
to how are we going you know what should
我们要怎么做，你知道应该怎么做
anybody who wants to use it any of the
任何想要使用它的人
tcks or any any of the binary material
tcks或任何二进制材料
how are they going to get support
他们将如何获得支持
switching over of things to point to the
切换事物以指向
jacquard EEE
提花EEE
branded documents or the required
品牌文件或所需文件
documents you can just join star the
您只需加入文件即可
github projects and watch them if you if
github项目，如果有的话请观看
you're interested and jump in and
你有兴趣，跳进去，
provide feedback I think a lot of people
提供反馈，我认为很多人
tend to think oh I'm not a developer I
倾向于认为哦，我不是开发人员
can't you know I can't really help them
你不知道我真的不能帮助他们
but if you're interested if you've got
但是如果你有兴趣的话
time we're ready to sign you up
我们准备签约的时间
so that's it for the sort of the summary
就是这样的总结
of this but I did want to talk a little
这个，但我确实想谈一点
a bit about a schedule I hate to meet
关于我不愿见面的时间表
tree visitor with us um Dimitri you
我们的树访客um Dimitri you
wanna sort of walk us through this oh
想带我们穿过这个哦
it's great
这很棒
yes this is the plain dumb job-creating
是的，这是无聊的工作
living in McCarthy ee8 must be released
必须释放居住在麦卡锡（McCarthy）ee8中的人
before check out the live stream which
在检查直播之前
is 10th of September and definitely
是9月10日
before Oracle : so we have too many news
甲骨文之前：所以我们有太多新闻
here we have creationary news for the
在这里，我们有关于
project and we have a final release
项目，我们有最终版本
video which takes a long time which
视频需要很长时间
takes a month we skipped actually all of
我们花了一个月的时间实际上跳过了所有
the reviews because if we have to reduce
评论，因为如果我们必须减少
then we won't fit into time we have
那我们就没时间适应
reviews a marked orange or non
评论标记为橙色或非
spreadsheet so the current date is today
电子表格，所以当前日期是今天
is 12 of June right it's highlighted
是6月12日，突出显示
smart here so we are at the middle of
很聪明，所以我们处于
basically the second batch of creation
基本上是第二批创作
reviews should start today and we will
评论应该从今天开始，我们将
have another week to complete creation
还有一个星期完成创作
of restructuring review in order to
重组审查，以便
create specification project the second
创建规范项目第二
task
任务
nonce next task is created a
随机数下一个任务创建
specification documents we can start
我们可以开始的规格文件
doing that then specification projects
然后进行规范项目
actually created and we have freebies
实际创建，我们有免费赠品
for that these supposed to be not really
因为这些应该不是真的
complicated tasks and hopefully it will
复杂的任务，希望它将
be completed on time at the same time we
在同一时间按时完成
should start on baking Java Docs update
应该开始烘烤Java Docs更新
Java Docs includes removing all juicy
Java文档包括删除所有多汁的内容
stuff from readme files and Java Docs
自述文件和Java文档中的内容
and put in correct information about the
并输入有关
clips chest there
夹在那里的胸部
and changing links and this kind of
以及不断变化的链接和这种
stuff at the same time we need to start
东西，我们需要同时开始
working on delivering tickets
运送机票的工作
actually yeah I'm looking at your own
是的，我在看你自己的
chart it started already and had already
图表它已经开始并且已经
explained that this is about TC case
解释说这是关于TC案
itself and the next task is about TC
本身，下一个任务是关于TC
case jobs for specifications projects it
规范项目的案例工作
means that each project has to create a
意味着每个项目都必须创建一个
Jenkins job which runs standalone TC
运行独立TC的Jenkins工作
case for this particular
这个特殊的情况
api's we need to make sure that updated
api，我们需要确保已更新
api we're not going to be binary updates
API，我们不会进行二进制更新
that will be Java Doc's need be hundreds
那将是Java Doc的数百个
but anyway we need some confirmation
但无论如何我们需要一些确认
that it passes the new TC case and this
它通过了新的TC案件，并且
task can be a little bit complicated we
任务可能会有点复杂，我们
were working with my folks to make a
和我的乡亲一起做一个
special not a special one drop which can
特别不是一滴就可以
be used as a template for other projects
用作其他项目的模板
so when it's done we will share some
所以完成后，我们将分享一些
information how we've done it so others
信息，我们如何做到的，所以其他人
can take it and make jobs for the
可以接受并为
project so everything I talked about so
项目，所以我所谈论的一切
far have to be completed before 15th of
必须在第15个之前完成
July so 15th of July is kind of the
7月，所以7月15日是
critical make the meter can you make can
关键使仪表可以吗
you so much zoom in we can barely see
你这么放大我们几乎看不到
the dates and you are talking something
日期，你在说什么
very important that means the D CK in
非常重要，这意味着
the deadlines thank you this is a media
截止日期谢谢你这是一种媒体
by the way hello everyone yeah
大家好
unfortunately my connections
不幸的是我的关系
not stable so I didn't hear everything
不稳定，所以我听不到
you said no you just said I just said
你说不，你只是说我刚才说
make it bigger than you did a little bit
使它比您做的大一点
so it's great thank you
所以非常感谢
I got your bigamy tree she just needed
我得到了她只需要的重婚树
it bigger we're good all right okay so
它更大，我们很好，好吧，所以
uh so the crucial dates are we will have
嗯，关键的日期是
release candidate tcks available the
发布可用的候选tcks
week of the 15th of July and then our
7月15日那一周，然后我们的
the the next crucial deadline is we want
下一个关键的截止日期是
to have all the specifications on ballot
具有投票的所有规格
or starting their ballot the week of the
或在
July 22nd that's to accommodate the
7月22日是为了容纳
30-day ballot review period and then
30天的选票审核期，然后
that gives us effectively a week to get
有效地给了我们一周的时间
everything buttoned up before the week
一周前一切都搞定了
of the tenth right so so those are those
第十个权利，所以那些是
are the dates we've been circulating
是我们流传的日期
this at the through the committee's but
通过委员会的
you know we wanted to let the yep thanks
你知道我们想让谢谢
Tanya we wanted to let the community
Tanya我们想让社区
know that those are the dates were
知道那些日期是
working on Demetri I think we were
我认为我们在Demetri上工作
getting the hook you wanna is there
得到你想要的钩子在那里
anything else you wanted to say no it's
你想说的别的是
it's so okay I see there's some question
很好，我看到有一些问题
or comments on the chat I don't know
或我不知道的聊天评论
I'll answer those off fine thank you
好的，我会回答的，谢谢
thank you
谢谢
Tania whoever's next or I guess it's
塔尼亚（Tania）下一个还是我猜是
either I'm sorry we were on mute on
要么我很抱歉我们沉默了
multiple devices so that's why I was
多个设备，这就是为什么我
talking into either so I think we're
谈论任何一个，所以我认为我们
expecting a update from Ivar just closer
期待Ivar更新
to projects exactly what's going on
准确地预测正在发生的事情
either
要么
are you there if you are your own mutual
如果你是你自己的共同体，你在吗
Oh so for the project names we are
哦，对于项目名称，我们是
pretty good
非常好
[Music]
[音乐]
as you see it's only a couple of project
如您所见，这只是几个项目
left's that we need to find lights on
左边是我们需要找到灯
the name so if anybody has any inputs or
名称，所以如果有人有任何输入或
any strong opinions about the names just
关于名字的任何强烈意见
comment on these issues for the scope
在范围上对这些问题发表评论
statements that we need for Jakari a is
我们需要Jakari a的语句是
a little bit the status there isn't just
一点状态不只是
as good so I think this is pretty
很好，所以我觉得这很漂亮
accurate but but here in the next couple
准确，但接下来的几个
of days we will start just writing Scott
几天之后，我们将开始写斯科特
statements for the project so if you're
该项目的陈述，所以如果你是
involved in any of these technologies
涉及任何这些技术
and you like to to have a say in what
你想对什么发表意见
the scope of the project should be this
项目的范围应该是这样
is the time if you go in and comment on
是时候进入并发表评论了
initiatives and as soon as the names and
倡议和名称和
the scope statements are are ready and
作用域声明已准备就绪，
approved by a committee we are
经委员会批准，我们是
initiating the restructuring reviews and
发起重组审查并
as you see we've started the review of
如您所见，我们已经开始对
five of these projects so as soon as we
其中五个项目，所以我们尽快
get the names over and we can batch this
把名字拿过来，我们可以批量处理
through the the process we will be
通过这个过程，我们将
getting all this fixed projects up and
整理所有这些固定的项目，
running so that's about the status of
运行，这是关于
the space and scope sentence and that's
空间和范围的句子，那是
about what I had to say it today so back
关于我今天不得不说的话
to you Tanya okay thank you Eva so I
给你Tanya好的，谢谢Eva，所以我
guess the next speaker is Wayne beaten
猜猜下一位演讲者是韦恩被殴打
and he will call he will actually talk
他会打电话说他会说话
about the JCP copyright licensing right
关于JCP版权许可权
here great so I thought I would just
这里很棒，所以我想我只是
kind of actually a lot of what ed said
ed其实说了很多
and a little bit of what the Ivar said
以及伊瓦尔所说的话
is actually in here but I figured I
实际上在这里，但我想
would go through it quickly anyway our
无论如何我们都会很快通过它
next step what we're working on right
下一步我们正在努力
now is to take all of these eclipse
现在要把所有这些蚀
project for prod
产品项目
we previously created these projects all
我们之前创建了所有这些项目
contain things like tcks and api's and
包含tcks和api之类的内容，
and in a couple of cases implementations
在一些情况下
of specifications none of them actually
规格，实际上都不是
include specification documents
包括规格文件
presently so what we're going to do is
目前，我们要做的是
going to take these Eclipse projects
将接受这些Eclipse项目
we're going to take the new name and the
我们将采用新名称，
new scope that statement that Ivar just
Ivar刚刚声明的新范围
spoke about we're gonna run it through
谈到我们要通过它
the release restrike army a
释放突击队
restructuring review which I've
我进行的重组审查
represented I think rather cleverly as a
代表我认为很聪明
transmogrifier I'm hoping people get the
转运者，我希望人们得到
reference and then magically we wind up
参考，然后神奇地结束了
with a specification project at the end
最后是一个规范项目
of this restructuring review there's a
在这次重组审查中，有一个
little bit of work for me to do here in
我在这里要做的一点工作
terms of updating project metadata
更新项目元数据的条款
updating the the nature of these
更新这些性质
projects and making sure that we have
项目并确保我们拥有
everything set up properly for
一切都为
specification projects but basically
规格项目，但基本上
it's a kind of a magical event that
这是一个神奇的事件
trends transforms these projects into
趋势将这些项目转变为
the right state
正确的状态
now as Ivar pointed out we do have a
正如Ivar所指出的，
github board set up to to track the work
设置github董事会来跟踪工作
that's being done here and as I gather
这是我在这里做的
the information or as I see that the
信息或如我所见
information is available from the the
信息可从
project teams regarding project names
有关项目名称的项目团队
and scopes I'm creating an in issue
和范围，我正在创建一个问题
issue in this board and that issue is
该董事会的问题，而这个问题是
being created in the in a github
在github中创建
repository that belongs to the project
属于项目的存储库
and so for example I will create a an
例如，我将创建一个
issue regarding converting the platform
有关转换平台的问题
jakar de platform project in the Jakarta
雅加达的jakar de平台项目
EE platforms git repository now having
EE平台git存储库现在具有
said that I think that's actually a bad
说我认为这实际上是一个坏消息
example because I don't think it has one
例子，因为我不认为它有一个
but that's the gist of it so basically
但这基本上就是要点
we're going to take all of these
我们将采取所有这些
projects and we're going to convert them
项目，我们将对其进行转换
into specification projects and I
进入规范项目，我
finally just give a couple of examples
最后只举几个例子
of what this will how this will manifest
这将如何体现
what we have now for example is the
例如，我们现在拥有的是
Eclipse project for servlet will become
Servlet的Eclipse项目将变为
Jakarta servlet
雅加达Servlet
the specification documents themselves
规格文件本身
which is what Kenya actually asked me to
肯尼亚实际上是要我这样做的
speak about right now the specification
现在说说规格
documents associated with all of these
与所有这些相关的文件
specifications are under age ACP license
规格未达到ACP许可年龄
that's a there's a variety of different
那是各种各样的
licenses but basically they are not
许可证，但基本上不是
under licenses that we can use in an
根据我们可以在
open-source specification development
开源规范开发
context an additional wrinkle is that
额外的皱纹是
while they're there they're under this
当他们在那里的时候，他们就在这个之下
license they are also in many cases
在许多情况下，他们也有
potentially owned by a variety of
可能归各种
copyright holders essentially anybody
版权持有人基本上任何人
who was on an expert group associated
谁在相关的专家组中
with a specification jsr could
使用规范jsr可以
potentially own copyright in these
可能拥有这些内容的版权
documents and in order to change a
文件和为了改变一个
license into a form that we can use we
许可成我们可以使用的形式
need their input their permission to do
需要他们的输入才能做
so so with this in mind we have created
因此，考虑到这一点，我们创建了
a an agreement to and have started a
达成协议并已开始
process of sending this agreement out to
将该协议发送给
the people who we believe might hold an
我们认为可能拥有
interest in these specification
对这些规范的兴趣
documents if you have received one of
如果您已收到以下文件之一
these it would be very helpful to us and
这些对我们和
the entire community that's forming
正在形成的整个社区
around your car to EE
开车到EE周围
that you sign this and return it to the
您签名并返回给
Eclipse Foundation this again the the
Eclipse Foundation再次
idea here is you will be giving us
这里的想法是你会给我们
permission to relicense the
许可重新许可
specification context in a manner that
规范上下文
can be used by the open-source
可以被开源使用
specification project so I'm just going
规范项目，所以我就去
to repeat myself the ask is if you
再说一遍我的问题是
receive a request for this could you
收到此请求可以吗
please respond if you have any questions
如有任何疑问，请回复
or concerns please make those known
或担心请告知
we've had a few people ask some really
我们有几个人问一些
interesting questions which I'm going to
我要去的有趣的问题
move into an FAQ because they're great
进入常见问题解答，因为它们很棒
questions if you're not sure please ask
不确定的问题请询问
and we're happy to help you work through
我们很乐意帮助您完成工作
this so once I have all of that
所以一旦我拥有了所有这些
copyright holder approval
著作权人批准
we can take the specification document
我们可以拿规格文件
source form which thank you very much to
源代码形式，非常感谢您
our good friends over at Oracle they
我们在甲骨文的好朋友
have taken all of the specification
已采用所有规格
documents that that they have they had
他们拥有的文件
in their possession and converted them
他们拥有并转化他们
from various formats including
来自各种格式，包括
frame-maker and and Tech and Microsoft
框架制造商以及Tech和Microsoft
Word and all sorts of different formats
Word和各种不同的格式
and have converted them into ASCII docx
并将它们转换为ASCII docx
format so I have those in my possession
格式，以便我拥有那些
and as we clear these documents as well
当我们清除这些文件时
as we have all of the agreements in
因为我们拥有所有的协议
place from all of the potential authors
来自所有潜在作者的地方
for these documents we are going to
对于这些文件，我们将
throw them into our transmogrifier and
把它们扔进我们的透湿器，
transfer them translate them into an EPL
转移它们，将它们翻译成EPL
2.0 license and then contribute them to
2.0许可证，然后将它们贡献给
the corresponding specification project
相应的规范项目
that we created in the previous step the
我们在上一步中创建的
details of this are I'm not sure how
这个的细节我不确定
important they are but the the projects
重要的是，但项目
that the teams that have been engaged
已经参与的团队
already in these projects are familiar
在这些项目中已经很熟悉
with our means of doing intellectual
用我们做知识的方式
property work our IP Zilla will transfer
知识产权工作，我们的IP Zilla将转让
them to those project teams through that
他们通过那个
we will of course communicate with the
我们当然会与
project teams as this is occurring just
项目团队，因为这正在发生
for note I put JCP license on my
注意，我将JCP许可证放在了我的
transmogrifier meaning whatever license
转化器意味着任何许可
they're currently in this is again is a
他们目前在这是一个
variety of licenses and I put EPL 2.0
各种许可证，我把EPL 2.0
because that was easier than saying that
因为那比说那容易
there is actually a variety of licenses
实际上有各种各样的许可证
most of our projects are EPL 2.0 some of
我们的大多数项目都是EPL 2.0，其中一些
them use I think there's a couple of
他们使用我认为有几个
using apache too but anyway so it's
也使用apache但无论如何
basically go from existing license to
基本上是从现有许可证
project license that's what I intend
这就是我打算的项目许可证
here once we have these specifications
一旦我们有了这些规格
in the repository transferred over to
在存储库中转移到
the project teams we're going to ask
我们要问的项目团队
those project teams to engage to update
这些项目团队参与更新
these specification documents to replace
这些规范文件代替
uses of trademark names that were not -
商标名称的使用不是-
we're not going to we have to be very
我们不会去，我们必须非常
mindful of
注意
other people's trademarks we need to
我们需要的其他人的商标
make sure that these documents do not
确保这些文件不
violate the trademarks of others and
侵犯他人的商标并
that they correctly use the names of the
他们正确使用了
projects and specifications as they will
项目和规格，因为他们将
be known under Jakarta ee8 there may
在雅加达（Jakarta）ee8下被人们知道
have been I've noticed just a small
我注意到只有一小部分
number of inconsistencies in the
不一致的数量
documents after being translated so some
翻译后的文件等等
certainly some sanity passes and sort of
当然可以通过一些理智的
validate that the content is accurate
验证内容是否正确
and correct and that there was you know
正确，那你知道
smooth out any anomalies that may have
消除可能存在的任何异常
occurred during transition at this point
此时发生在过渡期间
we require that the project teams not
我们要求项目团队不要
made substantial changes the Jakarta ee8
Jakarta ee8进行了重大更改
specifications need to be function
规格需要起作用
ordinated made to be in parity with the
使其与
the Jakarta or sorry the Java EE 8
雅加达或对不起Java EE 8
specifications so no changes to the
规格，因此没有变化
specifications please just kind of again
规格请再说一遍
work out the formatting and the
制定格式和
trademark issues please and we will
请商标问题，我们将
again continue to work with the project
再次继续与该项目合作
teams to ensure that this happens as
团队确保这种情况发生
smoothly as possible there will be one
尽可能顺利地会有一个
final transmogrification at the end once
最后一次迁移
we're all done and we have
我们都完成了，我们有
specifications and and we have
规格，我们有
specification documents all of the
规范记录了所有
projects will engage in release review
项目将参与发布审核
with this release review the
与此版本审查
specification document will change its
规格文件将改变
license to the eclipse foundation
蚀基金会的许可证
specification license and it is the
规范许可证，它是
version of this document that is
该文档的版本是
distributed under the eclipse foundation
在日食基础下分配
specification license that vendors will
供应商将提供的规范许可证
use to create their implementations and
用于创建其实现，以及
I just
我只是
is a picture I've I've displayed before
是我之前显示过的图片
you know the final specification is the
你知道最终的规格是
composition of all of these different
所有这些不同的组成
artifacts a specification document under
工件规格文件在
the specification license the TCK will
TCK将提供的规范许可证
also transmogrify and there will be an
也会变迁，会有一个
eclipse foundation TCK licensed version
Eclipse Foundation TCK许可版本
of the tia of that the technical
该技术的tia
artifacts would be api generally and
工件通常是api并且
then some number of one or more
然后是一个或多个
compatible implementations will be
兼容的实现将是
referenced as part of that final
作为该决赛的一部分被提及
specification and with that I believe
规范，我相信
I've come under the ten minutes
我来不到十分钟
allocated to me and I turn it back over
分配给我，我把它转回来
to you thank you so much thanks Wayne
谢谢你，非常感谢韦恩
I just put in the chat and I will say it
我只是聊天，我会说
out loud the questions are welcome in
大声地提问
the chat
聊天室
we just have tons of material to cover
我们只是要覆盖大量的材料
and we want to make sure we get through
我们要确保我们通过
it so but we also get through your
这样，但我们也可以通过您
questions either at the end on or we
问题在最后还是我们
will follow up later on so next we have
稍后会跟进，所以接下来
Scott Starck to talk to us about the TCP
Scott Starck与我们谈谈TCP
process and update on that front Scott
在此方面进行处理和更新
are you around
你在附近吗
yep good
是的，很好
are you sharing or are they looking to
你在分享还是他们在寻找
share okay great I saw you put your
分享好极了，我看到你把你的
slides earlier in the in the community
社区中较早的幻灯片
folder so just want to make sure that
文件夹，所以只想确保
you intend to be sure to share
您打算确保分享
good morning as cats let's keep thinking
早上好，因为猫让我们继续思考
let's keep this light while you are
让我们保持轻盈
finding representation in morning and
在早上寻找代表
night so everyone across the globe place
晚上，所以全球各地的每个人
on the column window
在列窗口上
Scott you you you want would it be
斯科特，你你想要的
easier for you if I share yeah sure
如果我同意，对您来说更容易
yeah I'll do that so let me just share
是的，我会这样做的，所以让我分享一下
my screen here okay thank you all right
我的屏幕在这里好，谢谢
so what I want to go over quickly is
所以我想快速讲的是
just the current status of our TCK
只是我们TCK的当前状态
process guide that we've been working on
我们一直在努力的流程指南
that's the last light there it's
那是那里的最后一盏灯
basically the highlights are that we
基本上，重点是我们
we've defined the contents that are
我们已经定义了
required for a TCK release namely that
TCK发布需要的是
there needs to be an open source version
需要有一个开源版本
of the TCK which can either be EPL or a
TCK的值，可以是EPL或
patch here the current approved licenses
在此处修补当前批准的许可证
those can be used for compatibility
那些可以用来兼容
testing without any restrictions in
测试不受任何限制
terms of additional licenses but those
附加许可的条款，但那些
cannot be used for branding rights
不能用于品牌权
there's a separate so I guess the last
有一个单独的，所以我想最后一个
or ratified version of the TCK that we
或我们已批准的TCK版本
license on the Eclipse Foundation
Eclipse Foundation上的许可证
technology TCK license which is the EFT
技术TCK许可证，即EFT
L acronym there that will be available
L的缩写，将在那里可用
after the specification has been
规范制定后
ratified and approved by the
经批准和批准
specification committee and then that by
规格委员会，然后通过
an area will be put up on to Carnegie
卡内基将建立一个区域
and will be signed for use for claims of
并将签名以用于以下用途
compatibility with rights to use the
与使用权的兼容性
branding and trademarks of Jakarta in
雅加达的品牌和商标
addition you need to define what content
另外你需要定义什么内容
needs to be part of that TCK which will
需要成为该TCK的一部分，
include user guides that define the
包括定义
software requirements how you install it
软件要求如何安装
configure it around the test any
围绕测试配置任何
specific rules for example setting of
具体规则，例如设置
databases JMS et cetera and there will
数据库JMS等，并且将会
also be a list of the current TCK
也是当前TCK的列表
excludes which are the listed tests that
排除哪些列出的测试
are currently under challenge and have
目前正面临挑战，并拥有
been accepted as currently not valid or
被接受为当前无效或
need to be updated and will be addressed
需要更新并得到解决
in future versions of the specs we also
在规范的未来版本中，我们还
define the mechanism by which a TCK is
定义TCK的机制
ratified made he made approved via the
批准使他通过
specification committee and then have
规格委员会然后
the EFT el binary signed and promoted to
EFT el二进制文件签名并升级为
the Dakota EE website that issue that
达科他州EE网站
bugzilla issue them reference there is
bugzilla发出他们参考
the current issue that we hope have
我们希望有当前问题
opened with the webmaster on how exactly
与网站管理员一起讨论如何
that process is going to be done for the
该过程将为
TCGA processes the next slide Tanya we
TCGA处理下一张幻灯片Tanya我们
defined the TCK challenge process
定义了TCK挑战过程
whereby someone can an implementer can
某人可以使实施者可以
challenge a test using the issue tracker
使用问题跟踪器挑战测试
for the specification project we define
对于规范项目，我们定义
the an equivalent process via which an
等价的过程，通过
implementation can come and claim
实施可以声称
compatibility and then gain access to
兼容性，然后访问
the branding rights and promotion via
品牌权和促销通过
the website then we defined an
该网站，然后我们定义了
escalation process for appeals and
上诉的升级程序和
grievances so if there's any issues with
委屈，所以如果有任何问题
the handling of a TCK challenge or you
处理TCK挑战还是您
know any any aspect of the TCK process
知道TCK过程的任何方面
or compatibility testing
或兼容性测试
how you handle that's been defined and
你如何处理已经定义的
lastly last slide please
最后最后一张幻灯片
the last two points that are under
最后两点是
discussion but aren't necessarily gating
讨论，但未必必定
factors for blocking the upcoming to
阻碍即将到来的因素
credit release are defining what the
信贷释放定义了
requirements are around how compatible
需求围绕如何兼容
products need to be kept in sync with
产品需要与
TCK releases as well as how do we add
TCK版本以及我们如何添加
tasks throughout the lifecycle of a TCK
TCK整个生命周期中的任务
for example to improve coverage without
例如提高覆盖率而无需
necessarily imposing an additional
一定要加一个
burden on implementers relative to an
与实施者有关的负担
update of the specification so that's
规格更新，因此
that's where we are as of today thank
到今天为止我们就是这样
you
您
I have a question for you this is Amelia
我有一个问题要问你，这是阿米莉亚（Amelia）
yeah it's got to tell me something what
是的，必须告诉我一些事情
do we have the documentation is still
我们仍然有文件吗
private or is a share already and the
私人或已共享，并且
repos well it's it's in a Google Doc so
仓库很好，因为它在Google文档中，所以
I'm not sure it's probably only
我不确定这可能仅仅是
available the specification can we get
可以得到的规格
this point okay um the the component
这一点好吧，组件
that affects the TCK user guide and the
这会影响TCK用户指南和
various projects we'll be rolling out to
我们将推出的各种项目
those as soon as we ratify that which
那些一旦我们批准
should be within the next couple of
应该在接下来的几个
weeks and then obviously producing a PDF
个星期，然后显然生成PDF
for that as well okay and if I wanted to
为此，如果我想
know about the timelines do you think
了解时间表，您认为
the specification committee will send
规格委员会将发送
out to the community not the working
向社区而不是工作
group to the community forum and update
分组到社区论坛并更新
with you know potential deadlines I
和你一起知道潜在的截止日期
think a level of transparency on the
认为
process as you specified
按照您指定的过程
without providing dates might be helpful
不提供日期可能会有所帮助
to bring those who want to contribute
带那些想贡献的人
your code and maintenance to be formed
您的代码和维护将形成
and participates be a peer review and
并参加同行评审，并且
everything else that goes into TCK
进入TCK的其他所有内容
waters yeah I mean well that's our goal
是的，我是说那是我们的目标
is to get there as soon as possible at
要尽快到达
this point so then we can expect an
这一点，所以我们可以期待
update to the community forum as soon as
尽快更新到社区论坛
you the specification committee
您是规格委员会
today's agreed correct yeah sure yeah
今天同意的是的，是的，是的
thanks God
感谢上帝
so moving on let's let's get the update
所以继续前进，让我们获取更新
on the discussion that is going on with
在正在进行的讨论中
regards to Javits namespace so David do
关于Javits命名空间，所以David做了
you want to take over
你想接管
you
您
tanja we have a question by edwin king
坦贾，我们有一个问题，埃德温·金
can you give me give him some space to
你能给我一些空间给他吗
ask in Edwina next time just raise your
下次在埃德温娜问一下
hand through this soon what we'd like to
尽快解决这个问题，我们希望
do is get through the agenda and then
要做的是通过议程，然后
we'll deal with the questions that yeah
我们将处理的问题是
yeah so I asked people to pose their
是的，所以我要求人们摆姿势
questions so Edwin thank you so much for
问题，爱德温非常感谢您
the question we'll get back well make
我们会很好地解决的问题
sure we address it yeah this is Paul
确保我们解决这个问题，是的，这是保罗
sorry I jumped in but just so everyone
对不起，我跳了进去，但是所有人
on the call understands we understand
在通话中了解我们了解
there's a lot coming here from as a from
从这里来的东西很多
a firehose the fact that we only have an
事实证明，我们只有一个
hour and we want to touch each of these
小时，我们想触摸每个
topics because we think each of the
主题，因为我们认为每个
topics is important to the community we
主题对我们社区至关重要
understand there's too many questions
了解有太多问题
related to each of these and so
与每个相关，等等
hopefully what will happen is the
希望将会发生的是
questions are either on the chat or
问题是在聊天中还是
perhaps even better afterwards you know
也许以后会更好
these questions can be raised and become
这些问题可以被提出并变成
threads on the community email list but
社区电子邮件列表上的主题，但
but we do want to make sure that
但是我们确实要确保
everybody has a chance to get through
每个人都有机会渡过难关
the topics so thanks for your for your
主题，非常感谢您的参与
understanding on that because we know
对此有所了解，因为我们知道
it's a lot and it's all time critical so
很多很多，而且都是至关重要的，所以
yeah so David do you have anything to
是的，大卫，你有什么要
share with us or and if you're talking
与我们分享，或者如果您在谈论
you're muted yeah David
你被静音了，大卫
looks frozen yeah you're okay
看起来很冰冻耶，你还好
so let's maybe until David figures out
所以直到大卫想通
so Mike de Nicola do you want to take
所以迈克·德·尼古拉你想参加吗
over yes I can do that okay fantastic
是的，我可以做到
I'll try to share my screen here yeah
我会在这里分享我的萤幕
let me know if you need help there world
让我知道你是否需要帮助
you know might be you look amazing
你知道你可能看起来很棒
this'll it's more chat very good well
这会更多聊天很好
you find your presentation that's
您发现您的演示文稿是
interesting
有趣
tendu can you can we use that can you
tendu你可以我们使用吗
show us frankly okay what you do that
坦白地告诉我们，你做了什么
yeah go ahead Mike okay
是的，迈克，好吧
all right the the the developer survey
好的，开发商调查
was was conducted in March of this year
是在今年三月进行的
and there were almost eighteen hundred
几乎有一千八百
participants and we there about eighteen
参与者，我们在那里约十八
hundred participants okay the goal of
一百名参与者好，目标是
the survey was to help the Java
这项调查是为了帮助Java
ecosystem stakeholders better understand
生态系统利益相关者更好地了解
the requirements priorities and
需求优先级和
perceptions of Enterprise Java developer
对Java开发人员的看法
communities the survey was promoted on
促进调查的社区
social media on the Jakarta EE website
Jakarta EE网站上的社交媒体
and through partners such as the lung
并通过肺等伙伴
the Java community and the Java user
Java社区和Java用户
groups the okay you
分组好吗
I'm seeing the TCK process I'm sorry
很抱歉，我正在查看TCK流程
something happened on my end and let me
我发生了什么事让我
just pull the fire again sure how are
只是再次拉火确定如何
you
您
that's it thank you so at any rate the
就是这样，谢谢，无论如何
top three community priorities for
社区的三大优先事项
Jakarta Yi turn out to be better support
雅加达彝族人得到了更好的支持
for micro services native integration
用于微服务本机集成
with Cuba nuts both hose actually tied
古巴坚果，两个软管实际上都系好了
as being the number one with 61% stating
排名第一的占61％
them as the priority and then the
他们作为优先，然后
product quality reference implementation
产品质量参考实施
at 37% which is actually quite a bit
占37％，实际上
below that the key item I think of the
下面是我认为的关键项目
survey shows that cloud deployments are
调查显示，云部署是
increasing over 2018 the native cloud
在2018年增加本机云
native is critically important today 32%
今天本地人至关重要32％
of the developers are currently building
的开发商目前正在建造
cloud native architectures and at night
云原生架构和夜间
and another 30% plant to do so within
另有30％的工厂这样做
the next 12 months the number of java
未来12个月的java数量
applications running in the cloud is
在云中运行的应用程序是
projected to increase significantly over
预计将大大增加
the next two years and with more than
在接下来的两年中，
60% of java applications in the cloud in
云中60％的Java应用
two years
两年
micro-services is the leading
微服务是领先者
architecture for implementing java
实现Java的体系结构
systems in the cloud with 43 percent of
云系统中有43％
the respondents citing that is their
受访者认为这是他们的
choice of architecture java ee 8
架构选择Java EE 8
adoption has picked up and it currently
采用率有所上升，目前
stands at 37 percent which is up quite a
占37％，上升了
bit from last year when we did the
去年我们做的时候
survey in 2018 it was only 21 percent
在2018年的调查中，这一比例仅为21％
Java EE 7 is 44 percent is the version
Java EE 7是该版本的44％
mostly for
主要用于
into production I can't see the bottom
投入生产我看不到底部
of this okay I got it
我知道了
with with Johnny six coming in third
约翰尼六世位居第三
Java 11 uses it surged and it looks as
Java 11大量使用它，看起来像
though people are leapfrogging
虽然人们在跳跃
Java nine and ten while Java 8 adoption
Java 9和10，而采用Java 8
has remained steady at about 84 percent
一直稳定在约84％
spring and spring boot continued to
春季和 spring boot 继续
dominate as the leading framework for
占主导地位的框架
building cloud native applications the
构建云原生应用程序
Eclipse micro profile growth is
Eclipse的微轮廓增长是
exponential with reputed usage
符合惯例的指数
growing from 13 percent to 28 percent of
从13％增长到28％
respondents in this year's survey the
今年调查中的受访者
top three titles of survey respondents
调查受访者的前三名
are the more senior developers
是更高级的开发商
architects 23% junior developers 19
建筑师23％初级开发人员19
which is up from 12% last year
从去年的12％上升
others were development managers team
其他是开发经理团队
leaders and small number three percent
领导者和三分之二的人
of c-level developers 60 percent of the
的C级开发人员中有60％
respondents work in organizations with
受访者与
fewer than 500 employees the top three
少于500名员工的前三名
industry verticals were the IT area
行业垂直领域是IT领域
which is not surprising the financial
这并不奇怪财务
services and education 56% of the the
服务和教育的56％
respondents survey are located in Europe
受访者调查位于欧洲
by Europe it's actually amia Europe
在欧洲，实际上是amia欧洲
Middle East and Africa 18% were from the
中东和非洲18％来自
asia-pacific 13% we're from North
亚太地区13％我们来自北方
America and 13% from the Caribbean and
美国和加勒比地区的13％
Latin America so that's not surprising
拉丁美洲，这不足为奇
since Europe is the Europeans I think
因为欧洲是我认为的欧洲人
leading the way in terms of enterprise
在企业方面处于领先地位
Java thank you so much Mike and just a
Java非常感谢Mike，
reminder to everyone these slides and
提醒大家这些幻灯片和
all other slides will be available in
所有其他幻灯片将在
the community drive okay let me just add
社区开车好吧，让我补充一下
one thing I meant to do this but Mike I
我想做的一件事，但迈克
want to quote Mike Milankovitch who said
想引用Mike Milankovitch的话，他说
what's most interesting is to see the
最有趣的是看
acceleration and the adoption of Java in
Java的加速和采用
new cloud native architecture which
新的云原生架构
clearly clearly the future of Jakarta EE
清楚地了解Jakarta EE的未来
is cloud native that was a quote from
是云原生的，引用自
Mike well link of the truth now on this
迈克好吧，现在就把真相链接
call thank you for that so are going
打电话给你，谢谢你
back to David I believe David's good too
回到大卫，我相信大卫也很好
are you good to go so let me share
你走的好吗，让我分享
scream alright so I'm gonna try and keep
尖叫好吧，我要努力保持
this brief we only have like 15 minutes
这个简短的我们只有15分钟
left it's obviously a very big
离开它显然是很大的
conversation it's a next time big stick
谈话是下一次大摇杆
you too small or less than 10 or 15
您太小或少于10或15
minutes we have you have a votes maybe
分钟，也许你有票
between five and eight then yeah that's
在五点到八点之间，是的
what I figured we have another topic
我认为我们还有另一个话题
after that's right so for that okay so
在那之后是正确的，所以这样
this is just a high-level summary of
这只是一个高层次的总结
where we had we had over 300 plus emails
我们有超过300封电子邮件
in response to the call to join the
响应加入的呼吁
discussion which is great the list
讨论很棒的清单
subscription on the jacquard any
提花订阅
platform dev is in the hundreds now
平台开发人员数以百计
when it was like 50 before we started
当我们开始时大概是50岁
and so that's just an amazing start to
所以这只是一个了不起的开始
our community this issue even though
即使我们这个社区有这个问题
it's very tricky has done a great job of
这非常棘手，
seating the Jakarta dev list with
与雅加达开发人员名单
participants which is what we need
参与者，这是我们需要的
ultimately in the long term so that's a
最终从长远来看，这是一个
very good thing in terms of where we're
就我们在​​哪里而言，这是一件非常好的事情
at I would say in the community there's
我会说在社区中
a slight lean towards BIGBANG maybe even
甚至对BIGBANG稍微倾斜
a strong lead there's in the steering
方向盘上有强大的领先优势
the specification committee that still a
规格委员会仍然
split and some people are not
分裂，有些人没有
necessarily some people are confident
一定有些人有信心
and some people want more data and so
有些人想要更多数据，所以
ultimately you know we established a
最终您知道我们建立了一个
deadline of June 9th and that was really
最后期限是6月9日
just for okay we need a month of open
只是为了好，我们需要一个月的营业时间
conversation before we can figure out
对话，然后我们才能弄清楚
what it's the next step and so at this
下一步是什么，因此在此
moment the next step is basically going
下一步基本上就开始了
to be to collect more data around a
收集更多的数据
couple specific points so the the the
几个具体点，所以
two primary area is where we want to
我们要去的两个主要领域
collect the data and the first one being
收集数据，第一个是
most important is want to do some
最重要的是想做一些
prototyping around compatibility to
围绕兼容性的原型
prove out these tools to see what they
证明这些工具，看看他们有什么
can do we also want to do some work to
可以做到，我们还想做一些工作来
analyze the dependency graphs between
分析之间的依赖图
different specifications so here's why
不同的规格，这就是为什么
these are really really important one
这些真的很重要
prototype and compatibility BIGBANG or
原型和兼容性BIGBANG或
incremental are completely impossible
增量是完全不可能的
proposals without the compatibility
没有兼容性的提案
being proven we knew that going into the
被证明，我们知道进入
proposals but that still seems to be a
提案，但这似乎仍然是
comfort factor for people who are voting
投票者的舒适度
or leaning towards an incremental side
或倾向于渐进式的一面
of offense that if the tools were
冒犯，如果工具是
proving to be stronger their appetite
证明他们的胃口更强
for being more aggressive would be
因为更加积极
higher and so I think the thing one of
更高，所以我认为这是
the major things preventing kind of a
防止某种情况发生的主要因素
unanimous decision is proving out these
一致的决定证明了这些
compact
紧凑
capabilities when we look at the
功能，当我们看
timeline of when we can do this we don't
我们何时可以做到这一点的时间表
think it's soon and so spending some
认为很快，所以花一些钱
time working on a compatibility at this
在这个时候致力于兼容性
moment is probably the smartest thing
可能是最聪明的时刻
that we can do for our industry at the
我们可以为我们的行业做的
moment
时刻
your work is encouraged there and I'll
您的工作受到鼓励，我会
show you how you can help or talk about
向您展示如何提供帮助或讨论
how to basically come to the jacquard
如何基本提花
e-platform project we're not doing to be
我们不打算做的电子平台项目
able to work in that project but we do
能够在那个项目中工作，但我们确实
want to enable that via that project the
想要通过该项目启用该功能
other one is an ad analyzing the
另一则是分析
dependencies the reason that this is
依赖的原因是
important is because it could be the
重要的是因为它可能是
case that if we changed one spec the
如果我们更改了一个规格
domino effect to all the other
多米诺骨牌效应
specifications is so great that the line
规格是如此之大，以至于生产线
because between incremental and BIGBANG
因为在增量和BIGBANG之间
is minuscule and not important and so we
是微不足道的，并不重要，所以我们
have started the work on dependency
已经开始有关依赖的工作
analysis and there's a lot you can do on
分析，您可以做很多事情
that I did a big push on that last night
我昨晚做了很大的努力
and I'll really like to show you some of
我真的很想给你看一些
that early data but ultimately what we
早期的数据，但最终我们
need to figure out is if we changed the
需要弄清楚的是，如果我们改变了
most popular specs say CDI jax-rs you
最受欢迎的规格说CDI jax-rs您
know being validation these types of
知道正在验证这些类型的
things
东西
what is the downstream effect of though
下游的影响是什么
of that change and so if you want to
的变化，所以如果你想
take a screenshot this is the one to
截屏，这是一个
take a screenshot of because it has the
截屏，因为它具有
link to the github URL so please do
链接到github URL，所以请
record that URL so you can join the
记录该URL，以便您可以加入
conversation there because ultimately
在那里谈话，因为最终
what we're trying to do is curate as
我们正在尝试做的是策展人
much data as we possibly can because you
我们可能会提供大量数据，因为您
know no human can summarize three
知道没有人能总结三个
hundred plus emails eloquently right
雄辩的一百多封电子邮件
that would be a several hour
那将是几个小时
presentation so effectively we're trying
演示非常有效，我们正在尝试
to do is get very very data-driven so
要做的是非常非常数据驱动的
some days after we started the
我们开始
conversation in the public we
我们在公众场合交谈
and collecting data here in the jacquard
并在提花机中收集数据
ee platform github project all of it is
ee平台github项目全是
in the sub directory namespace and I
在子目录名称空间中
want to point on a couple key documents
想指出几个关键文件
one is there's been a lot of fun or just
一个是有很多乐趣或只是
you know misinformation that all Java X
您知道所有Java X的错误信息
is affected is not and so this is a
不受影响，所以这是一个
curated list of Java X packages which
精选的Java X软件包列表
are in Java SE and absolutely not
在Java SE中，绝对不是
affected so the Java SE team has taken a
受到影响，因此Java SE团队采取了
look at this list for accuracy it's had
查看此列表的准确性
several eyes on it it's been curated and
几眼它已经被策划和
you can rely on it okay so these
你可以依靠它，所以这些
packages are absolutely not effective
套餐绝对无效
all right now in terms of this is the
就此而言，现在是
code that is actually under the umbrella
实际存在的代码
of jacquard EEE
提花EEE
these are the classes that are affected
这些是受影响的类别
so if this is a text file so if you'd
因此，如果这是一个文本文件，那么如果您愿意
like to start writing tooling to take a
喜欢开始编写工具
look at these classes you can do so so
看这些课，你可以这样做
this is a curated list of classes which
这是精选的课程列表
do which are effects this is not even
这样做是什至没有效果
generic like package this is the full
通用之类的软件包，这是完整的
list classes so this is the scope of our
列出类别，所以这是我们的范围
of what we're worried about
我们所担心的
and no no greater than this list ok the
且不超过此列表，确定
most important thing at this moment
此刻最重要的事情
though is you know or not the most
虽然您最了解还是最不了解
important things so the dependencies
重要的事情，所以依赖
between these two various projects is an
在这两个不同的项目之间
important factor that I mentioned so we
我提到的重要因素，所以我们
have begun to start curating data here
已经开始在这里开始整理数据
we do need more eyes and ears and and
我们确实需要更多的眼睛和耳朵，并且
and brains and hands on this data and to
和大脑和手上的数据，并
help collect data so last night I went
帮助收集数据，所以昨晚我去了
ahead and did the hard work of basically
前进，基本上做了艰苦的工作
writing a tool that used SM to parse all
编写使用SM解析所有内容的工具
the bytecode of all the classes under
下所有类的字节码
our control and do just basically a dump
我们的控制，基本上只是转储
a JSON dump of each class and its
每个类的JSON转储及其
dependencies right
依赖权
I miss if they can find one that has
我想念他们是否能找到一个
something right so here we go
正确的事情，所以我们开始
Java eggs batch property references
Java Egg批处理属性参考
Enterprise non-binding that's the CDI
企业非绑定即CDI
class ok so we need help basically
好的，所以我们基本上需要帮助
figuring out if we were to change say
弄清楚我们是否要改变说
CDI
CDI
one of the specs that are affected
受影响的规格之一
immediately and transitively we have had
立即和传递我们
somebody in the community do some work
社区里有人做一些工作
on this this is from a maven dependency
在这这是从一个Maven依赖
perspective purely and so what I noticed
纯粹是透视，所以我注意到了
that was a little bit is that our jars
有点是我们的罐子
in the Jakarta project are a little bit
在雅加达项目中有一点
inaccurate but the reason for that is
不准确，但原因是
some of them contain pride dependencies
其中一些包含骄傲依赖
which are not should not be in that jar
那不应该放在那个罐子里
for example the EJB jar contains jax-ws
例如，EJB jar包含jax-ws
dependencies and so it's these things
依赖关系就是这些
need to be cleaned up
需要清理
but please do take a look at this
但是请看看这个
particular document look at the
特殊文件看看
documents associated with to help create
与帮助创建相关的文档
some tools to do some analysis on what
一些工具可以对什么进行分析
exact scope of changes and help us
确切的变更范围并为我们提供帮助
figure out what is the actual Delta
弄清楚实际的增量是多少
between the incremental and BIGBANG also
在增量和BIGBANG之间
if you have any compatibility tools that
如果您有任何兼容工具
you're working on or like a start come
你正在努力或者像一个开始
here do a PR to this document and simply
在这里对此文档进行PR
list your tool we need like twelve on
列出您需要的工具，例如十二点
this page and so you know we I'm gonna
此页面，所以你知道我们我要
see the time but I would just basically
看到时间，但我基本上
say at this stage we want many projects
说在这个阶段我们要很多项目
doing attempts at compatible backwards
尝试向后兼容
compatibility in terms of bytecode
字节码兼容性
upgrading and so on so forth and then
升级等等，然后
will consolidate onto one or two once
将一次合并到一两个
they believe in themselves so this is a
他们相信自己，所以这是一个
most specific way you could call move
您可以称之为“移动”的最具体方式
the conversation forward at this moment
此时的对话
so I will let the last five minutes to
所以我要让最后五分钟
to the last remaining topic but you know
到剩下的最后一个话题，但你知道
please do follow up on the dev list the
请按照开发人员清单进行后续操作
trading platform dev list if you have
交易平台开发人员列表（如果有）
any questions or thoughts and we'll ask
任何问题或想法，我们会问
will answer questions there so Walter no
会在那里回答问题，所以沃尔特
thank you David so much will turn over
谢谢戴维
to turn over to Paul white or actually
交给保罗·怀特还是
my machine but in the meanwhile David if
我的机器，但同时大卫如果
you can see the question from Scott in
您可以在下面看到Scott的问题
the in the chat and respond there that
在聊天中进行回应
would be fantastic I have a have a repo
太棒了，我有一个回购协议
on my machine that I will open up and
在我的机器上，我将打开
make publicly available and we can all
公开可用，我们都可以
hack on that's together so that is an
砍在一起，所以这是一个
ASM based thing and yeah I will put that
基于ASM的东西，是的，我会说
Scott stuff thanks David thanks everyone
斯科特的东西，谢谢大卫，谢谢大家
so as Tonya said I'm Paul white and one
正如Tonya所说，我是Paul White，还有一个
of the things that I have the pleasure
我很高兴的事情
of doing is overseeing eclipse con York
做事是监督日食纽约
and and I wanted to call this out for
我想把这个叫出来
the community we participate and run
我们参与并运营的社区
into each other at a lot of events right
在很多活动中互相交流
around the globe be a dev ox or or
在全球范围内开发者或
whatever and those are great places for
随便什么，那些都是很棒的地方
us to welt and meet folks who are using
我们贴身和结识正在使用的人
this and whatnot the clips con Europe is
这就是欧洲短片
a place where we come together as as our
一个像我们一样聚在一起的地方
own in this case Jakarta community and
在这种情况下拥有雅加达社区，
it's an opportunity to work on things
这是工作的机会
that matter to share ideas and to make
分享想法并做出决定很重要
sure that we are advancing the community
确保我们在推动社区发展
so this is this is the one time of year
所以这是一年一次
where we get together as the as the
我们在一起的地方
Jakarta community as part of the Eclipse
雅加达社区作为Eclipse的一部分
community so there is a a dedicated
社区，所以有一个专门的
track for cloud native Java which is is
跟踪云原生Java是
all about Jakarta EE micro profile and
关于Jakarta EE微型配置文件和
and all of the other related
和所有其他相关
technologies and so we strongly
技术，所以我们坚决
encourage everyone to present to
鼓励大家出席
participate first and foremost by
首先参加
submitting a talk right so the deadline
提交发言权，所以截止日期
the early bird deadline for this is June
最早的截止日期是六月
30th and the early bird what that means
30号和早起的鸟意味着什么
is we select a handful of the talks
是我们选择了几个谈判
ahead of time and promote them heavily
提前并大力推广他们
so get your talking and early if it's
因此，请尽早开始讨论
selected then you will actually get
选择，那么你实际上会得到
extra promote promotion associated with
与之相关的额外促销
it but the overall call for papers it
它，但总体要求论文
runs through July 15 so as I say I
我一直说到7月15日
strongly encourage everyone to jump in
强烈鼓励大家加入
with the talk you know talking about the
与你知道的谈话
various issues that we have been trying
我们一直在尝试的各种问题
to move both forward car de8 out and
向前移动汽车de8和
then going forward but the other part of
然后继续前进，但另一部分
this that I don't have necessarily a
这个我不一定有
slide for but
滑但
all the events that are going around
所有发生的事件
eclipse con you are related to this
eclipse con您与此相关
topic so there is a community day on
主题，因此有一个社区日
Monday that is where we hope to it's a
星期一，我们希望在星期一
wide-open program at this point so get
此时要打开程序
involved in actually shaping what that
参与实际塑造
day looks like there also is a community
一天好像还有一个社区
evening on the Tuesday evening and we're
星期二晚上晚上，我们
actually arranging for a hackathon which
实际上是在安排黑客马拉松
really is just a name where we're trying
确实只是我们正在尝试的名称
to introduce folks new to this community
向这个社区介绍新朋友
to participate so it's a place for for
参加，所以它是一个地方
mentoring for building relationships and
建立关系的指导和
so we that's a new idea that we really
所以我们这是一个新想法
want to build on and we're hoping that
希望继续发展，我们希望
folks who are engaged here will actually
在这里订婚的人实际上
play a leading role anyway more to be
无论如何要发挥领导作用
said check out the program but but
说检查程序，但
that's just a highlight on it thanks
这只是一个亮点，谢谢
Tonya okay so we are just about to hit
托尼亚好吧，所以我们要打
the top of the hour I would like to I
我想去的最忙时间
think all the questions posted in the
认为发布在所有问题
chat were answered if you have any
如果有的话，聊天已被回答
follow-up questions please get in touch
后续问题请联系
and of course I am sure that you all
当然，我相信你们所有人
will have the calendar community
将有日历社区
calendar and you know that when is our
日历，你知道什么时候是我们的
next meeting scheduled in the meanwhile
同时安排下一次会议
follow us on Twitter Facebook Linkedin
在Twitter上关注我们Linkedin
and get involved in all of the aspects
并参与所有方面
of the jacquard EEE so thanks everyone
提花EEE，谢谢大家
and with this I will close the call and
与此同时，我将结束通话并
we'll be in touch
保持联系
thanks everybody thank you I
谢谢大家谢谢我
you
您